RUTURAJ MISHRA

Bangala Sahi, Athmallik, Odisha | 7752071060 ruturajm704@gmail.com

Summary

Experienced and self-motivated Network Engineer with 10+ years of industry experience with current profile as Project Manager since the last couple of months. I have a proven ability to establish and maintain excellent communication and relationship with clients. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as a part of a productive team.

Experience

Kwantify Solutions | Odisha, Keonjhar Project Manager | 01/2022 - Present

Here, I co-ordinate internal resources and third parties/vendors for the flawless execution of CUG & KJP projects. I ensure resource availability and allocation. Delegate project tasks based on junior staff members' individual strengths, skill sets, and experience levels. Develop a detailed project plan to monitor and track progress. Manage changes to the project scope & project schedule. Report and escalate to management as needed. Manage the relationship with the client. Develop spreadsheets, diagrams, and process maps to document needs. Perform other related duties as assigned.

CSM Technologies | Odisha, Bhubaneswar Network Consultant | 12/2015 - 12/2021

CSM Technologies hired me on retainership basis for its CUG Project to develop and maintain network infrastructure for their clients and assist their engineers on the escalated issues of networks, firewall, VPNs & ISPs. The CUG Project was an initiative of Department of Mines and Mineras, Odisha for the intranet & internet connectivity to its chekgates, weigh bridges and some PSU sectors like OMC over wireless broadband network. I was also responsible for the new intranet & internet connection architectual design and execution planning of the CUG networks. Along with this, I was also handling the network equipment insurance claim initition and settlement. Since it was not a full-time office job, I was persuing my B.Tech in Computer Science Engineering while working at CSM Technologies.

Info Services | Odisha, Bhubaneswar Network Engineer | 07/2014 - 11/2015

I was deputed at Airtel Bharti House data-center, Infocity, Bhubaneswar on behalf of IBM as a Network Engineer during this period. Info Services was an authorized partnet of IBM for this project. Here my job role was the installation, configuration and trouble-shooting of network devices of CISCO, JUNIPER & IBM. Apart from this, ticket creation for link down or fluctuation issues of WAN, LAN, & Wireless links, network diagram preparation or modification, report preparation was an integral part of this project.

Adocs Systems | Odisha, Bhubaneswar Assistant Network Engineer | 03/2010 - 07/2014

Being an assistant network engineer, my main job role was the installation, configuration and trouble-shooting of network devices like switch, Router, Modem etc. I was also looking the issues of computer systems and its softwares, printers. Network diagram preparation and other report preparation was also incorporated in my job role.

Skills

IP Subnetting, VLAN, Inter-VLAN routing, VPN, Firewall Web Filtering, Firewall Application Filtering, Firewall Policy Creation, OSPF, RIP, EIGRP, MPLS, BGP, MPLS VPN

Education

Matriculation | Athmallik, Odisha Mahendra High School | 11/2000 Pass Percentage: 54%.

+2 Science | Athmallik, Odisha Athmallik College, Athmallik | 03/2002

Division: 1st.

Graduation (CBZ) | Dhenakanal, Odisha Dhenkanal Autonomous College, Dhenkanal | 03/2005

Division: 1st

MCA (Distance Mode) | Bhubaneswar, Odisha SHUATS | 03/2014

Grade: B

B.Tech (CSE) | Khurda, Odisha Maharaja Institute of Technology | 08/2021

CGPA: 7.65

Languages

English, Hindi, Odia

Certificates

CCNA Security: CSCO12902754, Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP): 10212248

Declaration

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is correct up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above-mentioned particulars.

Place: Athmallik

Ruturaj Mishra